Utsav Baral

Chyasundol, Kathmandu, Nepal

J +977-9865544909

manutsssav@gmail.com | Inkedin.com/in/utsavbaral7 | G github.com/utsavbaral007

Profile

I have been creating websites and web applications for a little over two years as a UI/UX and React.js developer. Developing user-friendly platforms that they enjoy interacting with is my passion. I like utilizing a range of technology and design concepts to ensure that users have a smooth experience. I graduated from Tribhuvan University with a master's degree in computer science and information technology.

Education

Central Department of Computer Science and Information Technology, TU

Oct. 2021 - July 2024

Masters of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology

Kathnamdu, Nepal

Himalaya College of Engineering

Nov. 2014 - Aug. 2018

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology

Lalitpur, Nepal

Experience

InfoDevelopers Pvt. Ltd.

June 2021 - October 2021

UI/UX Engineer

Lalitpur, Nepal

- User interface development for corporate pay and connectIPS, two digital wallet systems.
- User interface and web application development for Ministry of Federal Affairs and General Administration (React.js).
- User interface and web application development for Government Integrated Office Management System (React.js).
- User interface and web application development for the digital lending system (Rapi Money), website and dashboard of the Nepal Police, Ministry of Health, Ministry of Land Reform and Management, and Sanima Bank Limited's subsidiary (Vue.js and React.js).

Oct 2020 - June 2021 Prismasofts

Software Developer

Kathmandu, Nepal

- Development of Real Estate Website using React.js, Node.js and Firebase.
- Development of Customer Data Management Web App using React.js, Node.js and Firebase.
- Development and maintenance of Prismasoft's website using React.js and Node.js.
- React.js basics and responsive web design mentor for new interns.

Learngaroo Learning

June 2020 - Sept. 2020

Web Developer

Kathmandu, Nepal

- Internship at Learngaroo Learning.
- Built REST API using Flask.
- Used AWS services such as S3 bucket and Transcribe.
- Created the Learngaroo homepage with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript..

Incwell Venture Pvt. Ltd.

May 2019 - May 2020

Bootcamp, Intern, Software Developer

Lalitpur, Nepal

- Involved in development and maintenance of in-house project, Leave Management System (LMS) developed using React.is.
- Developed Black Forest website using HTML, CSS and JS.
- Received hands-on training in web development technologies such as, React.js and Node.js.

Projects

Portfolio Website | Next. js, Nodemailer, Framer motion, shaden

August 2024 - Present

- Personal Porfolio website developing using Next.js.
- Used Framer motion for animation between pages while changing the routes.
- Nodemailer used for email services.
- Shaden used for UI Elements.

Automatic Number Plate Detection System | Python, Tensorflow, Keras

December 2023 - July 2024

- ANPR System developed using CNN.
- Used YOLOv8 for extraction of number plates from vehicles.
- Compared VGG19 and ResNet50 to determine the highly accurate model for recognition.

${\bf Instagram~Clone} \mid \textit{MERN Stack}$

- June 2020 July 2020
- React.js, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB were used in the development process.
- Used JWT for authentication, Context API for state management.

COVID-19 Tracker | React.js, Chart.js, Leaflet

January 2021 - February 2021

- COVID-19 Tracker web app developed using React.js.
- Chart.js is used for visualization of the data.
- Leaflet is used for displaying the stats on a map for different countries.

E-commerce web app UI | React.js, SCSS, Bootstrap

March 2022 - March 2022

• E-commerce website UI developed using React.js, Bootstrap and SASS.

Technical Skills

Languages:HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript(ES6), Python

Libraries/Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, Redux, Context API, SCSS, Bootstrap, Ant Design, Tailwind CSS

Technologies: Git, BEM Methodology, REST API, Responsive Web Design